> > Jem Young: 让我们先开始练习，先练习。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So let's start off
with an exercise, first exercise.
我们只会在命令行上弹弹一点点
We're just gonna play around with
the command line, just a little bit,
只要你舒服就好
just iin case you're comfortable.
我知道你们有些人有富尔萨克的经验，这很棒。
I know some of you have some
Fullsac experience, which is great.
你们中有些人从未接触过指挥系统
Some of you have never touched the command
line, other than, maybe doing Git or
就像这样
something like that.
所以只要玩玩就知道你不会破坏我的
So, just play around with it, knowing
you're probably not gonna break anything I
说也许我不在你的电脑里而且我不知道你在做什么
say probably cuz I'm not at your computer,
and I don't know what you're doing.
我不知道你是否坐在家里看 Netflix的沙发上
I don't know if you're sitting on
a couch at home watching Netflix,
而不是真正的关注
not really paying attention.
别担心我今天不会带你走太远的
But don't worry, I'm not gonna
lead you too far astray today.
命令行已经是命令行了
The command line has,
well, it's a command line.
它有不同的指令来做事情。
It had different commands to do things.
这些是一些比较熟悉的，我一直使用的。
These are some of the more familiar ones,
and the ones that I use all the time.
今天我们要用 cd 的
Today, we're gonna use cd a lot.
这只是移动目录
That's just moving directories.
Pwd 很有用，总是像我的密码，但是
Pwd is useful,
it always looks like password to me, but
是打印工作目录
it's print working directory.
其实我现在就做一些例子。
Actually, I'll just do some examples now.
所以就在这里执行
So, oops, execute over here.
如果要清除，您就可以在命令行中输入明文。
And if you want to clear you can just
type clear in your command line.
所以如果我想说 pwd，意思是我用斜杠，我在我电脑的根目录中。
So if I wanna say pwd, which means I'm in
slash, I'm in the root of my computer.
Ls 会列出所有档案我可以说
Ls is gonna list all the files and
I can say, ls,
我会用砍伤的方式说
actually I'll say cd into slash etcd.
现在我在等你
Now, I'm in etc.
后面的 cd1 不见了只有 cd1
And the back out cd1 to go nowhere,
just cd1.
你可能很熟悉 synod
You're probably familiar with the synod,
如果要获取同一目录中的文件，只需点斜杠。
if you want to acquire a file in
the same directory, you just dot slash.
Cd 点点表示移动目录。
Cd dot dot means move up directory.
点点表示移动两个目录，等等。
Dot dot dot means move up two directories,
etc., etc.
我知道我要去做基本的工作
I know I'm going over the basics.
这才是今天要走的
That's how this day's going to go.
我们会慢慢起步的
We're going to start off really slow.
这么慢你就像我为什么来这里
So slow, you're like, why am I here?
伙计这不是我能一直看的不好的主意我不知道体育舞会
Man, this is bad idea I could have been
watching, I don't know sports ball or
什么东西
something.
但我在这，我们正在做这些基本的事情。
But I'm, here,
which we're doing these basic things.
但我们要慢慢来我们需要命令行
But we start off slow we will
need the command line, so
和它一起玩
play around with it a bit.
猫真的很有用如果你想把文件给你
Cat is really useful if you wanna
file you just cat a file and
只要打印输出就好了
just print out the output.
伙计我们会用的因为你不知道所有的命令
Man, we're gonna use, just because
you won't know all the commands.
如果你想知道我们能做什么
And if you're ever curious
about something we can do
像猫一样把猫的手拉上来
things like man cat and
it pulls up the manual for cat.
总是有用的，我说的是男人的页面，不是所有的阳光和玫瑰。
Always useful, I'll say this about man
pages, are not all sunshine and roses.
在 Linux 的土地上一切都很好，一切都很有道理。
Everything's great in Linux land and
it all makes so much sense.
人的页面不容易阅读。
Man pages are not easy to read.
我推荐的通常只是查询搜索， Google， Bing，什么
What I recommend usually is just doing
a query search, Google, Bing, whatever
首选搜索引擎用于您尝试使用的实际命令。
your preferred search engine is for
the actual command you're trying to use.
但是用这个男人页的基本点告诉你
But for basic things using the man
page just tells you what it's supposed
如果你想搜查你就能找到刀把我不知道猫
to do and if you wanna search you can
type slash and I don't know, cat.
它会拉起东西
And it pulls up things.
我可以它一直在动
And I can, it keeps moving.
而要退出，只需输入 q。
And to quit, just type q.
我有一些关于杀人和所有这些事的笑话
I had some jokes about man kill and
all these things, but
我觉得他们不合适
I thought they were inappropriate.
没有吗
No?
他们不合适
They're not inappropriate.
所以杀人只是杀死一个过程的一种方式。
So kill is just a way
of killing a process.
我们希望不要用杀戮来做任何事情。
And we hopefully won't do anything
that requires using kill.
但如果你被困在某个地方
But if you get stuck somewhere and
有一个过程就是我要怎么杀死它
there is a process just
running how do I kill it?
您按流程名称开始终止。
You start kill by process name.
Pkill 是有用的，因为它不使用正在运行的东西的想法，
Pkill is useful because instead of using
the idea of the thing that's running,
我只能输入 pkill 节点，而我没有任何节点进程正在运行，但是
I can just type pkill node and
I don't have any node process running, but
它会杀死你的节点进程
it'll kill your node process.
由于工作节点过程中的 [LAUGH] 挂起，所以我使用了很多
This one I use a lot because [LAUGH] at
work our node process gets hung up and
这很令人沮丧
it's frustrating.
没事的没事的
It's okay.
如果你想删除文件 rm 很解释
If you wanna remove file,
rm, pretty explanatory.
Echo 重复一个文件或对输入的任何内容重复输入。
Echo repeats a file or
repeats an input for whatever you type in.
Ls 是有用的， ls 就像猫，只会显示一切。
Ls is useful, ls is like cat
except cat displays everything.
所以如果你有一个兆字节文件，猫就会把它丢在你的屏幕上，
So if you have a one megabyte file,
cat will just dump it all to your screen,
有时你会想有时你不愿意
which sometimes you want,
sometimes you don't.
Ls 就像一只更好的猫，一次只做一页。
Ls is like a better cat,
where it only does one page at a time.
所以它比猫更有用，但我们可能会在两者之间切换。
So it's a bit more useful than cat, but
we'll probably switch off between both.
如果要创建目录 mkdir，请除去目录 rmdir。
If you want to make a directory mkdir,
remove directory rmdir, yeah.
这对任何人都很熟悉吗
Is this familiar to anybody?
你之前大概都见过这一切但是
No you've probably all seen
most of this before, but
把它放在一个结构上是好事
it's good to kind of lay
it out as a structure.